hello everyone thank you for joining
this is the
recorded and live onboarding session for
the first cohort of
the active inference textbook group
and this
session is going to cover
many of the sections of our coda and
hopefully resolve your uncertainty about
participating in different aspects of
the textbook group
so there will be some presentations but
also a ton of time for questions so feel
free to use the chat
box on the bottom right hand side
to add any questions
um hello welcome
feel free to use the chat box on the
bottom right side to add any questions
and also feel free to raise your hands
and then we'll be able to see that hand
raised if you'd like to ask your
question but also it could be really
helpful just to add it in the chat
during this presentation so
you can click on the screen
that's being shared to see
it zoomed in
and so
you should be able to see my info screen
and some clicks
all right
so
welcome everybody to the actin flap
whether it's your first time
participating in
actin flab or in anything related to
active inference
welcome hope that this is like
a space where we can really
have some amazing things happen
this coda
that we're all looking at and that we
all have access to is our shared
epistemic niche and so you can of course
have your own notes and own documents
but this is our shared collaborative
niche
we are working through the textbook and
learning active inference this recent
textbook by par pizzulo in fristen
and by right clicking you can download
the pdf
full or the one where the pdf pages and
the book pages are aligned
just in case you wanted to download it
and it's also awesome that it's an open
source textbook
if you ever have any questions about
anything related to participating in
the textbook group or in any aspect of
actin flab then
activeinference.gmail.com a good email
address to contact
okay
so i'm gonna in the sidebar go to this
second one rules and also this sidebar
can be shown or hidden with the two
arrows so first we'll go over some of
the rules
and also with the understanding that
this is an evolving
area
and it's our first cohort so just
super appreciative and it's really
awesome for those for many different
places and stages who have stepped up to
engage in this way
and
we stipulate that by engaging with this
coda and in the live meetings so not in
private conversations not in your own
private documents but within the shared
spaces that are synchronous and
asynchronous that we're creating
together
we're in a participatory open science
space
and that means that
no proprietary or inappropriate
information will be shared
and that
more positively any ideas and writing
and contributions that are shared in
this shared coda
or during these recorded
sessions that we'll have
these are understood to be
declared as creative commons ccby
attribution so state otherwise or don't
say it if it's different because that's
how it's going to be understood in the
comments
and then of course if somebody's like
interested in this area of attribution
and all of this in in online spaces in
participatory communities that's an
important area
during the course of the textbook group
we are students
so we're interacting here as individuals
on the path of learning and applying so
some of us might be interested in
research as well and there will be
hopefully a ton of time to connect and
find those collaborations but we're
going to keep the regime of attention
on the learning the familiarity
accessibility and competency of active
inference as it is in that textbook that
doesn't mean it's going to be the only
document that we look at other resources
are going to come into play but it's
about learning
not research and we're interested in
this textbook that's what's bringing us
together
and
please be an engaged learner however
that means for you so whether you're
checking in once in a while
and just asking some questions here and
there
adding a comment like by selecting text
and then on the right side hitting the
add comment
whatever that kind of participation
looks for you or maybe you're
interested in re-skilling and in three
months you'd like to be in a totally
different position and you're
approaching this in a multiple hours per
day way we just hope that your
participation is open and authentic and
again if you have any questions about it
you can email
the next page we'll look at is the
directory so the directory has links
to the different sections of the coda
and anytime you see like a blue
link with an emoji next to it that's
something you can click on and go to
that page
so this has just descriptions on what
the different pages are
and it's what the onboarding is and it's
also this like an asynchronous
onboarding page if something's unclear
again you could just say i'm not really
sure about this
what does it mean to do dot dot dot
okay so that's kind of the
preliminaries is just welcoming those
who are new and returning to actin flab
stating some of the rules and bases for
our shared experience and then just
describing the structure of this coda
the next thing that we're going to talk
about is the onboarding
and feel free during this or any time to
to add those questions into the
chat
okay so here in the onboarding
section
as a participant you have total access
to the coda and the knowledge base here
which we're going to be exploring in
this session
and so we
suggest that especially for those who
are new to coda they may want to watch
this playlist that covers some of the
basics of coda and
there's also people to ask if you have
any questions but it's something like a
cloud document and a wiki because we do
have a version history
although it's also easy to make edits
and you'll find that some pages are
locked like this page cannot be directly
edited in the text by a participant
however they're able to modify these as
many many have already done
so
um we're going to talk about like the
student workspace and student practices
and things like that
and then to
help this sort of
self onboarding that everyone can go
through
we have several things that you can do
and engage with right now
so first what you can do is add your
name into the onboarding checklist table
below and fill up the relevant
checklists
so this is referencing another
table which is the list of students so
these are just the people who have
rsvp'd and then
people have selected and we can add new
rows people have selected from this drop
down or by typing their name
they can select
and then can add check boxes
when they have completed different
stages of this onboarding so here's just
a few things that people can do
you can have the physical textbook which
is pretty cool also it's the free
download like we discussed on this top
page
you may want to plan the time in your
own calendar for when and how you're
going to work
even if you don't know what the details
are we're going to talk a lot about
practices but you might just want to say
okay doing two hours in this block on
this day or i'm going to try to come to
this weekly session time
people are also welcome to add links to
their own personal or active blog
platform this is an affordance that not
everyone is required to engage in
nothing is mandated it's totally just a
service and an experience that we're
co-creating in this first cohort but you
may want to
have some short or medium or long
writings
about your reflections and about your
learnings so you may want to add this
blog and it's cool some have already
done that
and then
we offer
this student workspace and the student
workspace you can click on that link and
you head over to here
and there's a link that allows you to
open a new coda template
and use this template and so that copies
this to your code account so
the template was created by activelab
however
it is not going to be like viewable or
anything so this is not
something part of the textbook group
shared cohort um coda this is just going
to provide some tables and some
templates for you to play around but
also be potentially
tracking your progress in various ways
next we're going to go to the student
practices but
would alex or yvonne or anyone like to
just mention anything about onboarding
or the student workspaces
yeah i can give quick review on it
just
could you could you
open
the list
here
uh what practice is
uh
this one this one
student practice is okay it's okay also
yeah
here is the table that
help you to
track your
trick your study
so
we understand that the textbook is
not
not easy to read and not easy to
find time to
have a study on it
so this practices
will help you to keep your attention
during the whole
free
months
when we will
study it
so
we have
a
small description on each
on each
practice and
you can even understand
what they are
by its
name
[Music]
go through it and if you will have some
questions
just let us know
thanks um
that takes us perfectly to this student
practices which is kind of the question
of okay we set the groundwork
we onboarded ourselves onto
the textbook group using these
checkboxes
and now we're ready to like participate
and to engage with the content which is
going to be almost entirely asynchronous
we will have some live sessions like at
this time or potentially at other times
that others scaffold however it's going
to be about the learners engagement on
their own terms and times with the
content and so that is where
drawing on some practices from other
areas
we have constructed this table of
student practices
so it's kind of like a grab bag or a
tool kit where people can
find some affordance for their
participation so if you ever find
yourself
uncertain on how to participate in the
textbook group or uncertain on how to
increase your familiarity or your
competency in active inference
these are practices
that you can reach for
and you can add comments and also we can
absolutely add
to the practices we can add rows we can
add descriptions and products
but these are some regimes of attention
some tasks you can engage in
which
will help you
become more familiar with the material
and so there is this practice of like
thinking by speaking in dialogue joining
the synchronous meetings or arranging
meetings of your own type
and then a lot of the other learning
practices are going to be
asynchronous
alex or anyone else would you like to
ask anything okay and yes i just fixed
the permissioning on the template so now
it should be possible for people to copy
the template over
and then just one other random coda tip
if you do control and scroll
or control and plus minus
that can make the text bigger or smaller
so that can be quite helpful sometimes
okay so alex or anyone else um
any thoughts on practices
uh yeah let me add something on these
practices um
we are organizing this textbook group
trying to provide
some kind of
new affordances
to learning path
which will be more effective
if you're not just reading
the textbook by your own
but also communicate
inside this
shared epistemic niche from one hand
and from another hand
based on
our work on in education
on some of our projects we understand
that if you systematically applied some
learning practices
and tracking your progress
possibly day by day or week by week
with tools that also provided
in the template uh
you just from the beginning it's good
looks like some but some easy
stuff
but basically
after applying these practices for a few
weeks
you can figure out how it's really could
be helpful for you
we understand that
here different people with different
background different expertise
but for study groups let's just be
students again
and just apply these practices and it
will bring us
[Music]
more results that we even can expect it
for now
thanks
thank you alex
so um
we're gonna explore a little bit deeper
into the practices and then we'll talk
more about this
core
shared epistemic aspect of our coda
because of course if people wanted to
work alone
and not have any synchronous exchanges
with people and not have any shared
epistemic niche
they could do that on their own but
we're doing something with the textbook
group in the acting lab that's
collaborative and participatory
so as
seen in the
template but also on this page mastering
students
practices the practices are there to
help
keep our attention as learners
on
the material
through focusing on the practices
and so people can add their own columns
and explore but these are the kinds of
things where if somebody
could have high systematicity in
developing them
like approaching them in a very
systematic and comprehensive way
they would be learning and applying
active inference as works for them so
that's kind of a cool
way to have a self-paced and flexible
educational experience
and these are also just the pages that
are in that student workspace so it'll
be cool to see how these practices
develop
and
any comments or questions that people
have on them
does anyone want to raise their hand or
ask a question in the chat
the template is not working for people
right now
so
um
so i think are there two templates
there's like the checklist template and
then there's the student workspace
template i'm not getting the student
workspace one to work
as i see it doesn't work
when you
have a preview but
once you
push the button use template
it
became available for you
as anyone
where's the use template button
so
um what one thing also is people could
just
create a new code a document and then
copy
just ctrl c and copy it into a new
page so that will always work and the
template is not
vast
it's just these several tables so we'll
try to figure out the permissions
um
[Music]
okay
all right and also so i'm going to
unfold
some of these areas that we've spoken
about
and continue on with some of the
core epistemic components
of our coda and again anyone can raise
their hand
or can
add a comment in the chat yes rohan if
you would like to
ask your question
uh yeah so i'm not able to make copies
of this
template i'm so produce uh short once
again if you don't live
um okay so
um are you able to do to click these
three dots
and then do
copy to doc
and then copy it to a new doc
sorry that doesn't show up for me i'm
not okay
okay so then the it may just be because
like
i'm in the account that created it so
anyone can create a new coda document
like by clicking this back arrow
and then just creating a new document
and not kind of on that type of home
page
and then just
copy like you can just
go into this page and select the
content and copy it
and then just paste it into your coda
um
and we'll try to figure out the template
blue
so it did work for me if you on the
student workspace like the um red wheel
one
okay so not the orange one but the red
wheel if you click on the three dots
that are next to the workspace in the
sidebar there you go and click that and
then copy to doc that worked for me
it still may well it depends on what
somebody's access may be with um active
documents but
um copying will always work real hon did
that resolve it
uh okay so
i did that i could find the copy to dock
uh it made something not entirely sure
where it is now so so copy the dock and
then like we'll copy it to a new dock
and then oh okay and then now that's
totally your document so it's not part
of the action fork space at all
okay so i have to go back and then
search for it
yes it becomes so within the shared
epistemic niche within our shared coda
it's all like subpages in one url but
then once you copy it to your own doc
from a template or however it's going to
be your own url with your own sharing
privileges it's totally owned by you
okay yeah well i found it anyway yeah so
the copyright yeah great
okay so
can raise their hand if they want or ask
a question otherwise we'll continue on
to talk about um the ways in which we're
going to structure this collaborative
discourse on the material
so this discourse section has a few sub
headings
we have a page for ideas of the book
and so also if anything is ever like
unable to be edited
then just like but you feel like it
should be then just let us know because
we tried to permission things
to minimize the ability of someone to
accidentally like delete informative
text
and as much as possible we'll structure
things in tables
which should be editable so in the ideas
of the book these are like memes and
themes
what is active inference like when we
want to convey that to ourself and to
others those are the ideas
in chapter one this is an idea
and then there can be discourse on that
and these
buttons open up a canvas and you can
write things in there
we have um
questions this is a really important and
uh gonna be hopefully a very fascinating
and productive page
one coda affordance that's very
fun is at
is like calling a variable and that
could be anything from a person to the
name of a page a table or even a row in
a table
and so
the questions
can be
written in plain text but then also
people may enrich them
in this way and so we're going to return
to this question but first i just want
to show what equation 2.1
is
where is it coming from
so here in the equations section we have
another table with all the equations
right now just equation 2.1 has been
added
what is the name of the equation
what is the picture of the equation
screenshot
what page what chapter and what are some
tags which we'll talk about soon too
but
this is something that one person has to
add one time
then go back to questions
when
something is blue with an at you can
mouse over it or you can click on it
so then
how is equation 2 1 related to markup
blanket
is something that's very accessible
it's interactive we can have it
translated into multiple languages like
the terms we've already translated as a
lab into seven languages and especially
if people have a language that they'd
like to improve or add this can just be
added and so these kinds of
questions that we all raise up so
whether or not you do this like
ultracoda version or you just want to
write it in plain text and have somebody
else improve it
this is going to be able to create
computationally accessible
representations of questions that are
very clear
and also answers that are very clear and
there can be multiple answers in a lot
of discourse
but then those are addressing what
are
some answers to that question that like
a person may have
and
again uh
it's awesome if a question instead of
like
coming from an ill-specified
pointer and a
unclear regime of attention of course we
have uncertainty that's what the
question is representing but also we can
ask it in a way where even if we totally
don't know
what i don't know what equation 2.1 is
showing
i don't know what the markov blanket is
but by asking it in this way there's
like a conversation to have and people
can upvote interesting questions
and then again
we'll add the figures
as rows in the figures
the equations
here so then someone can say how does
figure 1.1 relate to action what was
figure 1.1 ah okay how does figure 1.1
relate to
ok action
those are just some of the ways in which
we'll be able to
have this
really
special
interactive space so that was that
questions page where we'll just be
building tons and tons of questions
and whether you write them initially in
your own private workspace or you want
to write them here
another important aspect of the
questions
is that the textbook doesn't have any
exercises or questions of any kind
and so this is like
in this first cohort and in this
textbook group
in general we're
in a sense creating some questions and
clarifying
adventures around
this textbook itself
as learners so that's the questions page
in the live meetings
page
we write that all are encouraged to join
these live meetings
or watch their video recordings where
we're going to be going over the ideas
of the book and the questions
the timings are noted here
of this
weekly time slot and what the theme or
the regime of attention is going to be
and also you've been added to a calendar
using the email you signed up for or you
can add these links in
and then if
somebody wants to
propose a one-off time or a recurrent
time
where they want to co-work
or they want to do these sessions they
absolutely can do that and we can update
the textbook group calendar here
the video recordings will be posted
to these links afterwards
and in this first meeting we're having
the onboarding session now
this is going to set
a
pace for moving through the first five
chapters of this textbook over the next
three months
and there's plenty
to dig into and plenty of rabbit holes
to explore
and so some might go
read ahead or
be behind you know life happens and
we're accommodating of that but this is
gonna set
a rhythm and a pace
where we'll be able to go okay we're
gonna talk about chapter one so what are
we going to do we're going to go to the
ideas of the book and the questions
we're going to look at what are some
ideas in chapter one
what are some questions that are tagged
with
specific references in chapter one and
what has been upvoted if there's too
many to discuss and then that is gonna
be the structuring of the regime of
attention so it would be super helpful
if somebody especially wants to like be
speaking and asking questions about it
the material to put in the time before
to add those so that people can
parse it and really consider your
question and your ideas
beforehand
because
there's differences in our language and
our familiarity with active inference so
sometimes the spontaneous
rant
is difficult for
others to parse and
structuring our questions
and writing the ideas down and helping
improve how each other's have shared it
will be a really important shared
practice
and then we can have people in the live
meetings taking notes on the questions
and so then if somebody does have a
spontaneous thought arising in
relationship to a question
or some discourse on an idea
we can absolutely record it and
and make that something that persists
rather than just uh a sort of
offhand comment in a video chat
so those are the live meetings and the
calendar
and we're in gather right now and so
there's some
information on if you'd like to for
example enable
various features of gather
including adding live text captioning to
your video if that's like something
you're interested in
but this is just a little bit of a
technical note on how to use gather and
some of the affordances of gather
okay
i cannot find the raise your hand button
i have not used it on an ipad
um but
on the bottom there's a hand
that raises your hand and also it stays
raised unless you unraise it and then
it's also there in the emoji
and all the emojis are transient
except for when you hit um the hand or
when you hit just six
from your computer then that raises your
hand
but um ali if you want to ask a question
then please feel free but first um okay
rohan then yvonne
oh no i was just testing
six thing
sorry great okay seems like you were too
yvonne so great
okay
so
we have project ideas
so here was a suggestion by a
participant
so
as with
many suggestions
this is our editable space we're the
first cohort of the textbook group so
however we want to do this
we can do it
feel free to list any project ideas here
so this is a fully editable page people
can just add
wouldn't it be cool like if there was an
audiobook recording i don't know
maybe that's something that somebody
else will see as a very exciting
opportunity so you can add different
project ideas and then
we've provided a template for some
tables that you can copy out
that are kind of like questions that
will help provide some overview
information
on your project optional of course just
like everything or add columns add rows
delete it's all up to you
and
questions that are about the situation
that you're seeing that is motivating
that kind of a project idea
and help you get some initial
structuring around like how you would go
about doing that
and this will get your idea from the
sort of
format here into something maybe that
other people could get on board with
so that's in the discourse um because
these are like really
content
and perspectives that
as a textbook group we're going to be
adding and creating
in this textbook section
it's going to be really focused on the
textbook as that core artifact so as
mentioned before there's the special
pages and tables
with the figures equations and the boxes
so then oh yes
at
b o x space 2.1
enter
at box 2.1 oh okay
there it is
and then people can have any questions
or comments and so on and then that
could be referenced in a question
somewhere else
what does at box space 2.1
mean for
um there's also these chapters and so
the chapters
are
listed here and linked so you can click
on five and go to chapter five
there's also a detailed table of
contents which
may have been created by dave or he
found it but he sent it to us and this
is like a really
fine-grained
look at the sections of the book
and whichever column in a table
as this ribbon
is the one that's called the display
column
so you can have like a set as display
and so that means like
um i was reading at 1.4.2
and this happens
it's page 11.
so every row
and all of its associated columns
can be referenced anywhere within this
coda you won't be able to reference
these rows in another coda
but this is like our shared commons of
information where we're able to enrich
the rows and create rows for each other
and that will hopefully create kind of
like a snowball effect with our digital
stigma g
because people will be able to ask
amazing
well supported questions
and then those questions themself
when
blue
asked
how is equation 2.1 related to this
here's what it made me think of so
there's like a structuring
to the way in which we can use certain
pieces of information and so again we
have the textbook section with the
chapters
and like we're starting on chapter one
and these are a lot of concepts and area
where people can explore
now you'll see that a lot of terms
have this at and they're blue so let's
look at where that is coming from and
that takes us to the last section of our
coda and then we'll spend the last 15
minutes with just
discussion and questions
the um
somebody has asked does coda allow text
to be formatted with latex thank you
brock for sharing the link
and um
yes if people would like that that's
something we can absolutely do
additionally we could um have a column
here
insert column after
and this can just be the latex
representation for example
so then you can copy and paste that to
allow people to modify it or to use it
in another work
okay so where are these core terms
coming from
in active inference tables we have a few
different tables
that are
prepared and created also in a
collaborative way
in other projects of the actin flap
so those who are participating in the
lab may know about some of these
projects but for those of you who might
be joining the first active lab
activity right now here's what these are
about
so active inference ontology
you can go to this link
and see the public version of the actin
phontology so this is like a link you
can share with anyone
and it has two pages there's the
definitions
of
core terms
which we'll return to and then there's
the translations
so here we have
i'll edit and resolve this but for core
terms
we have spanish portuguese french
italian czech russian and hebrew
so if there's a language that somebody
has some familiarity with even if you
only know some of it
it would be super helpful
to start to work in the dot edu
organizational unit of active lab on
this ontology project because we're
really
focused on making this accessible to
those with different mathematical
backgrounds and also different
speaking of different languages so it's
an awesome way even if you don't know
that much active inference to translate
some terms
and potentially bridge into a totally
new area
those tables
are in
our coda here so there's like another
coda that's holding the actual
um ontology and then this is a cross
document poll which we can like sync and
so that's one of the really important
and powerful features of coda so
each of these terms
can be called using an at so at
action space
planning
and then clicking that
enables the definition to pop up and
there's a ton of other columns but we
just wanted to pull a simple version
so the ontology
page
is hosting the table
that is giving the definitions of
different ontology terms
and also there's the public site
the live stream
table
has many many papers
some may be familiar or not that we've
done
150 plus live streams
the
live streams in the round table section
have to do with active lab updates and
strategy
in the live stream section
these are
on papers and so you'll find 46 papers
that we've been discussing over the last
however many months
and these are like great if you want to
dive into any of the papers that are
listed here
the guests stream
are
visiting
presentations and discussions
that
different individuals in the sort of
active or adjacent areas are presenting
on so if anybody has like a
recommendation or a connection or would
like to present on a guest stream these
are scheduled on a more ad hoc basis but
they have tons of awesome
uh
areas and applications
model stream is more specifically about
modeling
and um one of particular note is this
four part series with christopher white
and ryan smith on the step-by-step
active inference guide which is like a
paper that is very very similar to the
textbook it's not exactly the same of
course but it also walks through a lot
of the things that the textbook walks
through
um then an org stream is about
organization and so we have also some
other formats that haven't been used too
much and we have this um
symposium that we did with carl fristen
last year so this live streams table is
just if you feel like listening or
watching some live streams on any number
of a ton of different topics related to
active inference that we've done as a
lab and these are ones that you can
participate in like if you want to talk
about some of these papers you can join
a live stream
then there's this active inference
research
tab which is just sort of a partial view
but it's been work with blue and our
colleague rj
where we're working to be able to
reference papers
in a very rich and interactive way
inside and outside of coda so you'll
find the abstracts and some information
on several hundred active inference
papers
in case you're looking for it
but there's also a lot more to this so
if you're interested in knowledge
engineering and in curating active
inference research and annotating
research and these types of tasks then
this is like a awesome area
that takes us through the sections of
the coda
so just to recap info contains some
information on pre-onboarding with the
rules and directory and then the
onboarding itself which everybody is
welcomed to carry out for themselves
student workspace provides some
templates and ideas which you can
elaborate on and so on but some ways
that you can stay on top of
carrying out the student practices and
so anytime you're uncertain about what
actions to engage in to reduce your
uncertainty about learning and applying
active inference these are always things
that you can do
in the discourse that's going to host
some of the material and the discussions
that we're having synchronously and
asynchronously around the book
about the ideas in the book and the
questions that are raising up
and also hosting some project ideas that
people are rising up or seeing as
potentially relevant
then the textbook itself
is going to host um
[Music]
unpacking and connections of the content
in the chapters and also with a special
focus on this annotation of the figures
equations boxes and so on
that will allow the rest of the coda to
be like referencing the book
very clearly
and then there's the active inference
tables which are just showing off a few
of the coda features and a few of the
other projects in active lab and
so
that will be
at least the initial conditions of
our
coda and it'll probably evolve a lot in
the coming three months
so
that concludes the more presentation
aspects
of this onboarding session
for the next 15 minutes
anyone can type a question into the chat
or can raise their hands and we'll
hear from them
and then what's coming up next
is
over the next week we'll be
reading chapter one
engaging with the practices as they
relate
to
chapter one planning to read chapter one
investing time in reading chapter one
writing notes
adding a little blog post
asking questions about chapter one
talking to your
friends or family or active colleagues
about chapter one working with the
formalisms in chapter one
if people would like to there's a
totally optional link here
that they can use a hypothesis
annotation of the pdf so just it's there
if people want to but as with all these
practices they're totally optional and
this is like an off-site thing
um
and then
we'll continue on
so
that is um
yes okay roland asks
thanks for coordinating this are the
authors going to be participating at all
so we're in contact with the authors and
i won't speak for them into their
degree of participation in the future
which is unknown but they're excited and
hopefully happy
that
we're engaging in this way and we are in
contact with them but if there's some
other piece of information we can
provide sure
also they'll be watching the recorded
videos at least one of the authors
so yes
yes some of them may view some recorded
videos and they have access to the coda
and it would be awesome
for example
to have questions that we don't know the
answer to
maybe they do know the answer but also
maybe they don't and maybe there's
somebody here who does or there's
another author
who we can contact
um the textbook is a
a summary and a distillation and a tip
of the iceberg of a lot of ongoing
research
and so
asking those questions and then also in
the active lab we have
um relationships and ways of engaging
with many authors and relevant people
hopefully
so
we could
make it happen if it's important to make
it happen
ron or anyone else with a question
in the chat or
with their hand what is something that
people are just
excited or
motivated motivated about
what do they do
daniel did you not hear rohan no i it
says connecting for me sorry about that
oh yeah so rohan just asked a question
um maybe i think um he might need to
reload but
his question was will there be any code
involved at all what is the preferred
like platform for writing code or is it
just math
thanks
so
appendix c uh yeah i'm sorry about that
sometimes this does happen like as the
recording will show um you're just
connecting and so in those cases where
it seems like two people in gather like
are having a misconnection like one or
both people can reload and it usually
fixes it so sorry about that um
in the code section there's going to be
a few ways to engage with the code
one thing is that appendix c
is an annotated matlab
um code
so especially um in the older work
related to
spm statistical parametric mapping and
some of the earlier active inference
work matlab was the primary language
that was utilized
more recently there's been developments
in python and in julia
yes absolutely so pi mdp does offer code
so that's in python
and then another area of code that some
may be interested in developing in is
active block forms which is also
in python and was
initiated by jacob
and active block friends is implementing
active inference entities and
environments in cad cad which is a
complex systems design suite so that's
in python there's also julia
and some active inference methods in
julia
that are created by the bias lab
and
we also have created this repository
in github
for the textbook itself
so if anybody comments on this and just
says add me here's my github username
right here we'll add them to that
repository so if people want to do their
own code adventure of course great make
it happen um if people want to work in a
shop in a shared
code repository space
we'll have this
if people want to do any adventures in
python and julia and pi mdp and active
block brands and forney lab and all
these other amazing affordances they're
absolutely welcome to
we'll just remember that we're learning
the content of the textbook in the
textbook group and those are amazing
research and application avenues that
are super important and it's exactly
what learning active inference gets us
to the position of being able to engage
with
um
and i think
there's
as we'll maybe uncover um reasons why
the book is written primarily in natural
language
and figures and equations
it could have been a
notebook but it wasn't
so yes hopefully for those who are
computationally inclined
we'll have some code available
and also um again people can
raise their hand or ask a question but
um this is what the ontology
as we develop it and it's already far
more developed than this but if people
want to get involved here
one of the aims
is to have integrity across different
representations
of different human natural languages
different computational languages and
the formalisms in the analytical nature
of some of the core
of active inference
and so we can in the equations have tags
so
that will help us use ontology tags
to connect equations to
scripts
that are out there
using those same terms and so there can
be like a short blog article in another
language you don't speak
and a script in a computer language you
don't understand and a figure that you
didn't make but we can connect that
and generate and comprehend it in a way
that
may not have been done in other fields
or at other times so those are some of
the really exciting ways that we can
combine our perspective and our regimes
of attention
with appropriate collaboration so that
we can actually
learn and apply active inference better
because again if people just wanted to
listen to the
fristen lectures on youtube and read the
book alone
they absolutely can but to be engaged in
the textbook group is to be doing
something that's collaborative so hope
that addresses it
and
if anybody else wants to
raise their hand or ask a question in
the chat there's still time to do so
yeah in in the chat though what what do
people
expect and prefer
what would be epistemically valuable for
you
what would be pragmatically valuable for
on the top right you can switch from
light to dark
in the coda
just in case it looks very different for
you
so yeah this onboarding session
could have been about any topic
although we were looking at active
inference related themes and we're
setting up of course for the textbook
group we
didn't discuss any of the material
but that's exactly what is going to be
happening
in the actual weeks to come
so
if anyone has like any
kind of
notes they'd like to add in
for the people who are here and for the
people who may be re-watching this
recording
feel free to add anything again if
anybody wants to
okay
so i type the slash
which opens up coda affordances like
inserting any number of
things and then
inserting a table
and this will be
active inference
code
and so then we can start
go from the unstructured list to the
structured list
into the table
what language is it
is it a walk-through or is it something
for application and structure
that discussion around code
yeah thank you everybody who's um who's
joining we're
enacting the kind of epistemic niche for
active inference that we are
implicitly or explicitly
expecting and preferring so we might as
well
and and the organizing
we can also note was in edu and comms so
in two of our weekly active lab meetings
so there's a whole team and many people
contributed variously
to setting up this niche
and
set up the niche was all we did like
it's for us to actually co-create in our
learning
but
this was a
participatory project just like
everything in actin flap is so if
anybody is like wanting to learn more
about participating in other active lab
activities
on the top page
you can
learn more about becoming a participant
in academic lab as well so there's like
a ton of cool projects to get involved
in
including active block for instance a
lot of in the ontology educational
materials
future cohorts of the textbook group
and so on so there'll be a ton to do
all right
so that concludes the onboarding session
i'm going to stop the recording unless
anyone has any final thoughts
okay i'm gonna stop the recording